Benjamin Vaughan Papers 1746-1900 Mss.B.V46p
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. General Correspondence, 1746-1952; 6.5 linear feet (Box 2-27)
  - TLS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1780 February 8; 1 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Franklin requests more copies of his 5th edition of his philosophical papers.
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1780 March 26; 3 p.; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Priestley requests a copy of his letters.
  - TLS Cy to Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790, 1780 April 23; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Discusses the county and court politic in England.
  - TLS Cy to Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790, 1780 May 12; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Joseph Priestley is ill.
  - TLS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1780 June 15; 2 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1780 October 4; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Discusses his future.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1780 October 13; 9 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    considers a future profession.
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1780 October 30; 3 p.; Oliver, Richard,
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1780 November 29; 3 p.; Vaughan, Rebecca
    She discusses what she is reading and asks for his advice.
  - ALS to Vaughan, Rebecca, 1781 January 28; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    The letter is written on the same paper that Rebecca used to write to him. He edits her letter. He gives her advice on her writing and what books she should read.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, [1780]; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, [1780] 1, 2; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, 1780 February 11; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Notes on [Edmund]Burke's speech on presenting a bill for better securing independence of parliament, and economical reformations on civil and other establishments.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, [1780]; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1781 January 23; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Relates the events in Scotland. Mentions Adam Smith.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1781 February 20; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1781 February 22; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Discusses the Scottish clergy.
  - ALS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1781 February 23; 3 p.; Vaughan, William
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1781 February 28; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1781 March 4; 6 p.; Vaughan, Rebecca
    She relates to Vaughan the health of individuals.
  - ALS to Vaughan, Rebecca, 1781; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    His response is written on the same letter she wrote him. He corrects her grammer.
  - TLS Cy to Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790, 1781 May 31.; 3 p.; Jay, John, 1745- 1829
    Jay writes that Vaughan wished him to administer Vaughan the Oath of allegaince to the United States.
  - ALS to Crawford, Adair, 1748-1795, 1781 August 8; 7 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Jay, John, 1745-1829, 1781 August 20; 9 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1781 October 18; 2 p.; Oliver, Richard,
    Congratulations on Vaughan's marriage to Sarah (Sally) Manning.
  - TLS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1781 November 22; 2 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Congratulates Vaughan on his marriage.
  - TLS Cy to Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798 and Mrs. Bache, 1782 January 19; 1 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Letter of introduction of John Vaughan.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 February 7; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1782 February 21; 2 p.; Oliver, Richard,
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 March 3; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Treaty of Alliance.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 April 2; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Tdcy, 1782 April 5; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Memorandum on payment of a debt.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 April 10; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Livingston, Robert R., 1746-1813, 1782 May 14; 1 p.; Jay, John, 1745- 1829
    Informing hin that he is going to Paris as requested by Franklin.
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1782 May 18; 2 p.; Oliver, Richard,
    Letter of introduction for Dr. Clifton.
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1782 June 12; 1 p.; Oliver, Richard,
    Letter of introduction for Mr. McDonnough.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 June 17; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Discusses the employment of Mr. Lauren's secretary.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 July 6; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Will not be able to dine with Lansdowne that night on account of family matters.
  - Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1782 July 9; 3 p.; Oliver, Richard,
    Letter of introduction for Richard Down Jennings.
  - TLS Cy Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1782 July 10; 2 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Discusses nations laws of war.
  - TLS Cy Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1782 July 11; 2 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - ALS Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1782 July 31; 2 p.; Oliver, Richard,
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 July 31; 10 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Discusses the terms and resistences to peace with America.
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 July 31; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Handwritten copy of letter, with note on letter written by author.
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 August 6; 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Handwritten copy of letter by author. Discusses at length his conversations with Franklin on the War and the treaty with Britain.
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 August 17; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Handwritten copy of letter by author.
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 August 18; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 October 3; 7 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 October 7; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hand written copy of letter by author.
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 October 11; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hand written copy of letter by author. Gives his reasons for why Britain should accept the Treaty of Paris.
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 October 29; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 November 1,4; 11 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 November 5, 6; 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 November 23; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 November 24; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 November 27; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 December 1; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 December 4; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 December 7; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 December 10; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1783 January 5; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1783 January 12; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hand written copy of letter by author. Letter is marked private.
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1783 January 18; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1783 January 25; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hand written copy of letter by author. He discusses a Count Monstiers.
  - AMs, 10 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Miscellanious remarks on the treaty negociations between the United States and Great Britain in 1782.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 August 4; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS toVaughan, [Benjamin], 1751-1835, 1782 August 7; 4 p.; Faujas de Saint-Fond, Barthélemy
    Written in French.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 August 7; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 August 7; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 August 12; 1 p.; George III, King of Great Britain, 1738-1820
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 August 24; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 August 24; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 September 9; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 September 11; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AL and copy to Soulavie, L'Abbe, 1782 September 22; 17 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Letter "on some parts of the Theory of the Earth."
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 October 13; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALcy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 October 23; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 November 11; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 November 15; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLcy to Livingston, Robert R., 1746-1813, 1782 November 17; 9 p.; Jay, John, 1745- 1829
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of 1737-1805, 1782 November 21; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 November 22; 1 p.; George III, King of Great Britain, 1738-1820
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 December 8; 2 p.; George III, King of Great Britain, 1738-1820
    Type on the same page as the previous letter.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 November 27; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, "Article proposed", 1782 November 29; 3 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - AL to Vaughan, John, 1756-1841, 1782 December 15; 11 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 December, 17, 18; 7 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 December 18; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 December 22; 1 p.; George III, King of Great Britain, 1738-1820
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 December 24; 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 December 26; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 December 26; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 December 27; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1782 December 29; 8 p; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, [1782]; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy, [ca. 1782]; 1 p.; Jay, John, 1745- 1829
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 January 11; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ADS, Deed, 1783 January 13; 2 p.; Wheelwright, Joseph
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 January 14; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 January 15; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Vaughan is under house arrest in Paris.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 January 16; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 January 17; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 January 18; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Vaughan is concerned that peace will not be reached. Requests that Dr. Franklin visit Versailles.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 January 28; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Tmscy, 1783 January 28; 10 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Memorandum concerniing the preliminaries with France and Spain from Mr. Benjamin Vaughan.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 February 16; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 February 21; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 February 21; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Vaughan believes that the treaty needs altered.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 March 6, 7; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMScy Memorandum, [1783 March 6]; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Memorandum concering Mr. Eden's speeches about the Provisional Act, as given in the Morning Chronicle.
  - Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1783 March 8; 1 p.; Barnard, Jonathan H
    Requests Vaughan to advance Mrs. Margaret Stewert money for copies of the "Senator's Remembrances"
  - ANS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1783 March 8; 1 p.; Stewart, Margaret
    Promisary note.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 March 10; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 March 12; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 March 14; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1783 March 23; 1 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Franklin is considering publishing the account of the distruction of cities and plantations in the Colonies.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 March 23; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Discusses a Mr. Hodgson.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 March 26; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 March 30; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790, 1783 August 8; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to [Merrick], Rebecca Vaughan, 1783 November 14; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Vaughan's wife had a baby boy who he names Richard after Richard Oliver.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 December 2; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 December 3; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 December 14; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1783 December 18; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, [1783 December]; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TMScy Memorandum, [1783 December]; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    "Hints about an American Negotiation"
  - TMScy Memorandum, [1783 December]; 9 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    "Loose Hints concerning India and the present bill"
  - TMScy Memorandum, [1783 December]; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    "Of the system proper for an English minister at this juncture of Decr. 1783."
  - ANS, [ca. 1783]; 24 p.; Forster, Johann Reinhold, 1729-1798
    "remarks relative to a plan for the Foundation of a new National extensive and usefull Institution for the Education of Youth in America."
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1784 January 4; 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs to [Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805], 1784 January 10; 20 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1784 January 17; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, [1784] January 7; 1 p.; Oswald, Richard, 1705-1784
    Oswald is sick and cannot have dinner with Vaughan.
  - AL to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1784 January 20; 1 p.; Mr. Ord
  - Tmscy, Memorandum, 1784 January 25, February 9; 17 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    "New Queries & Remarks on India affairs."
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1784 January 28; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1784 February 2; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Vaughan wishes Lansdowne to interfere on behalf of Mr. Manning with Count Belgioso.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1784 February 24; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Laurens, Henry, 1724-1792, [1784 February 27]; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1784 March 21; 3 p.; Jay, John, 1745- 1829
  - AL to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1784 April 17; 1 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Vaughan injuried himself falling off his horse.
  - AMs, 1784 April 21 [read]; 4 p.; [Jean Baptiste Marie]
    Extracted from the Journal de Physique, May 1784.
  - AL to [Rittenhouse, David], 1784 June 25; 4 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Handwritten copy possibly made by Vaughan included.
  - TLS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1784 July 26; 9 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - ALS to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1784 August 9; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Manning, William, 1784 August 25; 2 p.; Woodley, John
  - TLS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1784 Spetember 7; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Letter of introduction
  - AMs, Manufactures minutes of meeting. Etruria, England, 1784 November 30; 4 p.
  - AL to Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820, 1784 December 20; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, Dec. 30, 1784; Sharp, Granville, 1735-1813
    Old Jewry, A.L.S. 4p. "No.4." (tipped in at the end of vol. 5 of Sharp's Works.) Concerning the Abbé de Mably's remarks on the American constitutions.
  - AL to Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820, 1784 December 31; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AL to Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820, [1785] January 2; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALcy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 January 1; 1 p.; Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820
  - ALcy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1788 July 2; 2 p; Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820
    Housed with 1 Jan. 1785 letter from Banks to Vaughan.
  - ALcy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, Sunday; 1 p.; Lady Lansdowne
  - ALs to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 January 17; 1 p.; Swinburne, Henry
    Vaughan's wife just had a baby.
  - ALS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 February 5; 1 p.; Washington, George, 1732-1799
    A letter of thanks.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1785 February 7; 9 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 March 5; 3 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - TLS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 March 14; 9 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1785 March 18; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1785 March 21; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1785 March 30; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 April 5; 10 p.; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    "An account of the progress of population agriculture & government in Pennsylvania, in a letter from Benjamin Rush M.D. Professor of Chemistry in the University of Philadelphia to Benjamin Vaughan."
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 April 21; 3 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    includes typed copy of letter and handwritten scene of a play.
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 April 21; 3 p.; Franklin, William, 1731-1813
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1785 June 2; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Als to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 June 4; 1 p.; Oliver, Thomas
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1785 June 13; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS Cy to [Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835], 1785 July 22; 3 p; Crawford, Adair, 1748-1795
    Includes, "Further Remarks by Dr. Crawford. The symptoms of the Stone in the Bladder are as follows."
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 July 23; 3 p.; Woodley, William
  - ADS, 1785 July 26; 1 p.; Franklin, William, 1731-1813
    Note for 48,000 livres drawn on Benjamin Franklin. Contains note by Benjamin Franklin.
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 July 29; 1 p.; Woodley, William
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, 1785 August 2; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 August 8; 3 p.; Jackson, Jonathan,
  - ALS to Manning, William, 1785 September 27; 3 p.; Woodley, William
  - ALS Cy to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 September 30; 2 p.; Romilly, Samuel, Sir, 1757-1818
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1785 November 13; 3 p.; Vaughan, Samuel
    Vaughan's father intends to purchase land.
  - ALS to Woodley, William, 1785 December 13; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Letter of introduction on behalf of Mr. Wise.
  - ALS to Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790, [1785] Wednesday; 1 p.; Williams, Jonathan.
    Brief note
  - AMs Parlimentary notes, 1785; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, [ca. 1785]; 4 p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Case of the stone. Includes copy.
  - Amscy, 1785; 3 p.; Watson, William, Sir, 1715-1787
    Opinion givne at a consultation on the case of Dr. Franklin in the year 1785.
    Hunter, John, 1728-1793; Hunter, John, d. 1809
  - ALS Cy to Hunter, John, 1728-1793, 1785 July 18; 1 p.; Heberden, William, 1710-1801
    Housed with 1785 opinion of Franklin's case.
    Hunter, John, 1728-1793
  - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1786 January 19; 1 p.; Wren, Thomas,
  - ALS to Wren, Thomas, 1786 January 21; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Written on same page as previous letter.
  - TLS Cy to Lansdowne, William Petty, Marquis of, 1737-1805, [1786 March]; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, April 1786; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Concerning the public debt.
  - Als to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1786 June 2; 2 p.; Woodley, William